Hello, Mr. Hindle,
亨德尔先生 你好
or as they called you around the hospital, Zepp.
或者像在医院里那样称呼你 泽普
Game over!
游戏结束
Check it, man.
你看 伙计
What the fuck is this?
这他妈的是什么玩意儿
What the fuck are you doing here?
你他妈的在做什么
I'm fucking stuck.
我他妈的被绑住了
Yeah, me too.
我也是
- What the fuck? - Oh, my God.
- 这该死的是什么 - 天啊
Somebody, help us.
快救救我们
- Hello. - Come on, help us!
- 喂? - 快点 救救我们
Oh, my God!
天啊
Dina.
狄娜
Brad.
布拉德
- Ryan? - Baby, are you okay?
- 莱恩? - 宝贝 你还好吗
- Get me out of here! - Baby.
- 放我下来 - 宝贝
Help us. Somebody help us!
救救我们 救救我们
Hey! Call the police!
快点报警啊
Hey, break the glass with your case.
用你的手提箱把玻璃砸碎
Break the fucking glass! Do it.
砸碎这该死的玻璃 快啊
Stay back!
退后
Do it!
快点
- Get me out of here. - Break it!
- 放我下来 - 砸碎它
Hello, Brad.
布拉德 你好
Hello, Ryan. I'd like to play a game.
莱恩 你好 我要玩一个游戏
The same woman has played each of you for a fool,
这个女人愚弄了你们俩
manipulating your love for her, and causing nothing but pain.
操纵你们的感情 给你们带来痛苦
Her fun and games pushed you
她诱使你们不惜犯罪
both to break the law to fulfill her material needs.
来满足她的物欲
She is toxic,
她是个蛇蝎女人
and today all of your transgressions will be made public.
今天你们所有的罪恶都将大白于天下
He's fucking lying, Brad.
布拉德 那个混蛋在说谎
Now you must choose who will drop out of this triangle,
现在你们必须选择谁将从这三角恋中消失
for within 60 seconds one of you must die.
接下来的60秒里 你们中的一个必须死
If you wish to save her, then the saws must be pushed
如果想救她
all the way to one side or the other,
就必须把电锯推向对方
sparing her while proving for good who is indeed the alpha male.
救了她的同时 也证明自己才是真正的男人
What are you fucking staring at, you motherfuckers?
我操你妈的 看什么看
- Do something! - Are you both strong enough
- 快想办法啊 - 这要看你们是否足够强壮
to walk away from what is destroying you,
来脱离困境
or will you fight one more time for the heart that binds?
或者为那颗纠结的心奋起战斗
You have 60 seconds to decide.
你们有60秒钟考虑
Live or die. Make your choice.
生或死 由你们决定
Oh, fuck!
妈的
One of you save me!
你们两个赶快救我
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈的要干什么
It's me or you asshole,
白痴 不是你死就是我亡
and it sure as shit isn't gonna be me.
而我绝对不会死
Brad. Brad.
布拉德 布拉德
Brad, I love you.
布拉德 我爱你
I love you too, baby.
我也爱你 宝贝
Do it. You gotta do it.
杀了他 杀了他
- What? - You gotta kill him, Brad.
- 什么 - 布拉德 赶快杀了他
- Do it! - Stupid bitch!
- 杀了他 - 愚蠢的婊子
Do it. Do it! Do it!
杀了他 杀了他 杀了他
Fuck!
妈的
You love him?
你爱他?
No, no.
不 不
You love him more than me?
你爱他胜过爱我吗
No, I had to say that.
不 我是被逼无奈
I've always loved you.
我爱的一直都是你
You got to do it for me, please.
为我杀了他 求你了
You got to kill him. Kill Brad! Do it!
赶快杀了他 杀了布拉德 杀了他
You lying slut!
你这个撒谎的婊子
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈的要干吗
You don't love anybody!
你谁都不爱
You're a cheat and a liar. Fuck you!
你是个骗子 操你妈的
Fuck you!
操
Brad! Brad, look at me!
布拉德 布拉德 看着我
Is the chick that fucked me
这个两天前在你床上和我做爱的婊子
in your bed two days ago worth one of our lives?
值得我们丧命吗
She's not worth it, man. She's not worth it.
不值得 伙计 不值得
Right?
对不对
Yeah!
对
What are you doing, you fucking asshole?
你想干吗 你这个混蛋
I think we're breaking up with you, Dina.
狄娜 我想我们要和你一刀两断
No! No, stop!
不 不 停下来
- Stand aside! - Move it!
- 靠边 - 让开
People, get out of the way.
请让开一下
Somebody help her.
赶快救救她啊
《电锯惊魂7》
Game over.
游戏结束
No! No, you fucking bitch!
不 不 你这个贱人
No!
不
Tonight, a house of horrors has been discovered
今晚 在罗文动物研究机构旧址
at what used to be known as the Rowan Zoological Institute.
发现了一处骇人的恐怖现场
The body of Umbrella Health CEO William Easton has been identified
其中一具受害者遗体被确认为是
as one of the several victims of this grizzly crime scene.
雨伞健康集团执行董事威廉·伊斯顿
However, we have also been informed that there may be
我们还得知
as many as seven survivers...
可能有七名幸存者...
Hopefully the many questions of the local police,
希望当地警局
the FBI, and the victims' family members may be answered
联调局以及受害者家属的诸多问题
by those seven civilians lucky enough
可以由这七位
to walk away from this unprecedented display
挺过这场无妄之灾的
of carnage with their lives.
虐杀幸存者揭晓
We now go live to Tony Gabrielson
接下来由托尼·盖布里森
who is reporting from the scene.
发来现场报道
(警视厅)
- Hey, man. - Hey, what's up?
- 好啊 伙计 - 好
What have we got here?
什么情况
That's Jill Tuck, Jigsaw's widow.
这是吉尔·塔克 竖锯的遗孀
What does she want?
她想干吗
All she said was that she didn't trust the FBI,
她只是说她不相信联调局
- and she didn't trust homicide. - Good.
- 也不相信罪犯 - 很好
And she just wants to talk to you.
她只想和你谈谈
- Why me? - I don't know. Only you, though.
- 为什么是我 - 不知道 但非你莫属
She looks crazier than a sack full of cats.
她看起来还真恐怖啊
All right, let's get this over with.
好吧 让我们赶快搞定
Hey. I put cream and sugar in it.
我加了糖和奶
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢 - 不客气
I'm Matt Gibson, internal affairs.
我是内务部的马特·吉布森
My colleague said that you wanted to speak with me.
我同事说你想跟我谈谈
Yes.
是的
But I need complete immunity.
我要完全豁免权
Why do you want immunity, Miss Tuck?
塔克小姐 为什么要豁免权
Because of what I know.
因为我所知道的一切
Which is what?
具体是什么呢
Do we have a deal?
成交吗
You've got to give before you can receive in this house, Jill.
吉尔 在这里你要先给予才有获得
My husband John, he had an accomplice.
我丈夫约翰有一个共犯
A person who assisted him with almost every murder.
一个协助他完成几乎每起谋杀的共犯
Look, don't get me wrong.
不要误会
I'm all ears if you've got
我在认真地听辨
something legit that you want to put on the table.
你所要公开的秘密是否合法
This person will go on killing until he's stopped.
这个共犯若无人阻止就不会收手
- You know him and he definitely knows you. - Is that right?
- 你知道他 他也知道你 - 是吗
He's detective Mark Hoffman.
他是马克·霍夫曼探员
Are you willing to sign a sworn affidavit?
你愿意签署一份宣誓书吗
Yes.
愿意
You swear to be totally open?
你发誓完全坦白
You tell me everything, no matter how personal or private?
告诉我一切 无论多么隐私
Yes.
愿意
I'll give you evidence, whatever you want,
我给你证据 你要的一切
as long as I have your protection, and complete immunity.
但你要保护我 给我完全豁免权
Do we have a deal?
成交吗
Oh, yeah. Yeah, we have a deal.
好的 好的 成交
Welcome back!
欢迎回来
We're live with Bobby Dagen whose national tour
我们正在直播波比·达恩
S.U.R.V.I.V.E. My Story of Overcoming Jigsaw
他的全国巡讲《幸存 我战胜竖锯之旅》
rolls into town this weekend.
本周末将登场
Well, you're quite the
最近你成了
national phenomenon these days, aren't you?
国民焦点 是吧
Well, thank you, ma'am.
谢谢夸奖
It's quite flattering how many people have responded to my story.
虽不敢说我的故事影响了多少人
And if I can help a few people along the way, then I'm pleased.
但只要我能沿途帮到几个 我就很开心了
Now, you survived a trap
你从声名狼藉的竖锯杀人狂的
created by the infamous Jigsaw killer, correct?
陷阱里逃了出来 是吗
Yes, ma'am.
是的 女士
Well, everyone must ask you this question. What was that like?
大家都想知道 那是怎样的
Life changing.
生活发生了改变
It was something I never anticipated
那是我始料未及的
and, quite honestly, something that should have killed me.
坦白地说 那本应置我于死地
Tell me more. Tell me about the actual experience.
多透露一点 告诉我具体的经历
I actually have no recollection of how I got there.
我不记得怎么到了那里
I just remember the feeling
我只记得醒来发现
of waking up trapped.
自己被困住了
And I had to insert two hooks into my pectoral muscles
而我必须用两个钩子穿过胸肌
and hoist myself up to a platform.
把自己挂到台子上
You put the hooks in yourself?
把自己挂起来吗
I did.
是的
I pretty much realized that I couldn't hold on much longer,
我清楚地知道自己坚持不了多久
and I had to accept the fact that I was going to die.
知道自己要死了
And then I saw something,
然后我看到了
and what I saw was my life.
看到了我的一生
It was a tragedy. I achieved nothing.
悲剧的一生 我一事无成
And right then, something inside me started to grow,
突然 我体内的某种东西在萌芽
something from the bottom of my soul.
来自我灵魂深处的东西
And I just...I decided to live.
然后我...我决定活下去
I found a strength that I thought had long since expired.
我萌生了一种早已泯灭的力量
And I just yanked, and I yanked!
我就猛拉 猛拉
And when I got to the top,
一够到台子上
I just ripped the hooks out of my chest.
我就把钩子拽了出来
There was blood everywhere, and I just screamed.
到处溅满了血 我在那里尖叫
I just sat there and screamed.
坐在那里 尖叫
Because I hadn't just survived,
因为我不仅仅死里逃生
I was reborn.
我已经涅槃重生了
This was my life.
这是我的人生
Wow. Bobby Dagen, everyone.
各位 这就是波比·达恩
Bobby's life- changing experience comes to the...
波比生命重写历程谈到...
This is the moment.
就是这个时候
- Where's the big kiss? - I don't know.
- 深情一吻哪儿去了 - 不知道
Tickets are still available.
巡讲售票仍在持续中
And we're out, folks.
结束了 伙计们
- That's not the way it's supposed to be. - You need to relax.
- 这和原计划不统一 - 你需要放松
No, we rehearsed it differently.
不 我们要重新排演一次
It's okay. Nice work, Bobby.
没事 干得好 波比
Ladies, can you excuse us for a minute?
女士们 可以回避一下吗
Where was the big finish, Bobby?
重磅结尾哪里去了 波比
You tell your story, you thank your pretty wife,
你讲述你的故事 感激你美丽的妻子
you bring her out for a big hug and kiss.
给她一个拥抱和深情一吻
I just didn't want to push it, all right?
我不想那样 不行吗
Okay, but that's the heart of the story.
好吧 但是那是故事的核心
She was there for your whole recovery.
她在你的整个复原中不离不弃
And without the acknowledgment, without the kiss,
没有感激 没有热吻
the audience isn't gonna have any kind of emotional connection.
听众不会有感情共鸣的
I disagree.
我不赞成
Too much emotion, and it's gonna feel like pandering.
太多的情感流露会看起来做作
Okay, why don't you let me do the public relations,
让我负责公关
and you do the legal paperwork, okay?
而你管好法律文书 行吗
Okay, I get it, Suzanne, all right? It's my fault.
好了 我知道了 苏珊娜 是我不对
It wasn't your fault, Bobby.
波比 不是你的错
You were fine.
你做得很好
- Just remember your bullet points next time. - I will.
- 只要下次记得重头戏就行了 - 我会的
These interviews are important.
这些采访很重要
Nina, relax.
尼娜 放轻松
Don't worry about them.
不用担心他们
You were great.
你很棒
Yeah?
是吗
Your story's real and people feel that.
你的故事是真实的 人们可以感觉到
I know that you get overwhelmed at times,
我知道你有时不知所措
but we have to keep moving forward, Bobby.
但我们不能放弃 波比
You were meant to do this.
这是你该做的
I know. I know, baby.
我懂 我懂 宝贝
- Bobby. - Yeah?
- 波比 - 怎么了
We got the Jigsaw survivor group tomorrow.
我们明天有个竖锯幸存者见面会
Thirty minutes of face time with other survivors.
半小时的会面时间
Yeah, sounds good.
好的 听起来不错
Nothing more exciting than that.
无与伦比的激动吧
No, not much. Let's go.
是的 很激动 我们走
(警视厅)
Oh, God!
上帝啊
You want to know the only thing wrong with killing you, Jill?
吉尔 你知道我杀了你的唯一遗憾是什么吗
I can only do it once.
那就是我再也不能杀你了
Oh, my God!
上帝啊
No!
不
(埃文)
Help me! Help me!
救命 救命啊
Help! Fuck!
救命 妈的
Hello, Evan. I want to play a game.
你好 埃文 我想玩个游戏
The situation you find yourself in is of your own doing.
你所处的环境都是你曾做过的
You, your girlfriend, and your friends are all racists.
你 你的女友和朋友 都是种族主义者
Evan, you fuck. You get me out of here!
埃文 干你娘的 赶快把我弄开
You have intimidated others based on their physical differences.
你因为别人的肤色而威胁他们
But today it is you who will run scared.
而今天轮到你胆战心惊了
Your pathetic friends follow your every word, Evan.
埃文 你可悲的朋友们对你唯命是从
Therefore you will be the
所以你将是
only one capable of saving them and yourself.
唯一能够挽救大家的人
In 30 seconds, the jacks holding up this car will fall,
30秒后 支撑汽车的千斤顶就会落下
setting off a deadly chain of events.
开启一系列死亡游戏
In order to stop this from happening,
为了阻止它
you must tear yourself away from the seat to which you are glued.
你必须把自己从粘着的座位上撕下来
Then you must pull the red lever before you.
拉动你前面的红色杠杆
But no act comes without a sacrifice.
凡事都有代价
You've judged others by the color of their skin,
你根据肤色来审判别人
and today, Evan, you will learn
而今天 埃文 你会学习到
that we are all the same color on the inside.
在内里 我们的颜色是相同的
Live or die, Evan, the choice is yours.
生或死 埃文 由你决定
No!
不
- Evan, help! - I can't.
- 埃文 救命 - 我做不到
- Do it. Fuck! - Fucking do it!
- 加油 妈的 - 该死的快点
Just fucking do it!
他妈的快点
Do it! Do it, man!
加油 加油 伙计
Here I go!
我来了
Evan!
埃文
Baby, get me out of here!
宝贝 把我弄开
Shit! Fuck! Here I go!
干他娘的 我来了
Here I go! Come on!
我来了 来吧
Fuck me!
我操
Please!
求你了
- God! - Do it! Fucking do it!
- 上帝 - 快点 他妈的快点
- God! - Do it!
- 上帝啊 - 加油
- Evan! - You got us into this.
- 埃文 - 是你把我们卷进来的
Get us the fuck out!
你他妈要把我们弄出去
Do it!
加油
You fucking pussy!
你他妈的孬种
Shit.
该死
Every night
每晚
I keep thinking that things will get better
我都祈祷明早当我醒来
the next morning when I wake up.
情况会有所改观
But it isn't.
但现实并非如此
Everything I do,
无论我做什么
everything I see, I'm surrounded by these
看到什么 都会让我
tiny triggers.
触景生情
They're everywhere,
它们无处不在
and they remind me of what I went through,
不断地提醒我所经历过的一切
what Jigsaw did to me.
竖锯对我做过的一切
Sidney, go on, please. You're...
西德尼 继续 你...
You're in a safe place now.
你现在是安全的
Tell me what happened next.
告诉我接下来发生了什么
Alex! Stop, please! Stop it!
亚历克斯 不要 求你 不要这样
Sidney, look at me.
西德尼 看着我
You made a decision.
你做出了选择
How did that make you feel?
这让你感觉如何
Free.
自由
He was abusive.
他是虐待狂
I tried to stop it before,
我曾试图了结那一切
but it wasn't until that moment
但直到我那样做了
that I really did something.
我才解脱了
It was him or me, and I chose to live.
不是他死就是我亡 而我选择活着
It was the best thing that ever happened to me.
那是我经历过的最棒的事情
That's a bunch of bullshit.
全是扯淡
He had to die for you to leave him?
为了放你自由他就必须死吗
You want to know the best thing that happened to me
你想知道我砍断手臂之后
after having to cut off my own arm?
经历的最棒的事情吗
It's handicapped parking at the damn mall!
就是可以在该死的购物商场免费停车
What the hell is a camera here for anyway?
那该死的录像机干吗用
I am simply here to
我来这儿只是想说明
illustrate the fact that a traumatic experience,
惨痛的经历
such as the kind that each one of us has been forced to endure,
就像我们被迫承受的这种
can have a positive outcome. That's all.
可以产生积极的作用 就是这样
Yeah? Like what?
是吗 比如呢
A new perspective on life. Wait, wait, wait.
对生活的新认知 等等 等等
I know. I understand that you're not at that place yet.
我知道 我理解你还没有领略到
I understand that and I respect that.
对此我给予理解和尊重
But if you look around at all these people
但如果你环顾四周
taking their lives for granted,
那些对生活无动于衷的人
eventually they all found
最终他们也会从自己的经历中
something positive from their experience.
收获一些积极的感悟
We should never be ashamed of what we've gone through,
我们不该为自己的经历而羞愧
because we are good and we are strong!
因为我们很棒很强壮
You know what?
你们知道吗
I'd like everybody to have a look at something right here.
我想给大家看点东西
These are my scars.
这是我的疤痕
Because our minds will heal,
我们的思想或许会被治愈
but these scars will never go away.
但这些疤痕将永不褪去
These scars should not be a symbol of shame.
这些疤痕不是耻辱的象征
They should be worn as a badge of courage.
而是勇敢的徽章
You know, earlier,
之前
I spoke of valuing your loved ones.
我提到要珍视你们的爱人
But to be perfectly honest,
而说实话
it's something that I never did prior to my ordeal.
在那次考验之前 我从未如此想过
But since then,
但那之后
I have found someone who has truly become my rock.
我认识到有个人一直默默支持着我
Joyce, if you could...
乔伊斯 你可以...
Please.
拜托
It's my lovely wife Joyce.
这是我的爱妻乔伊斯
- I love you. - I love you too, baby.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你 宝贝
Bravo.
真棒啊
To be able to sustain such a traumatic experience,
能够忍受这种惨痛的经历
and yet find the positive in that grizzly act,
还能够从中找到积极的感悟
it's a remarkable feat indeed.
真地太让人惊叹了
Remarkable,
惊叹啊
if not a little perverse.
虽然有点荒谬
I'm sure I speak for everyone here when I say
我确信在场的各位都觉得
how grateful we are
成为你促销光盘中的一部分
to be part of your promotional DVD.
荣幸之至
I appreciate it. Thank you.
非常感谢 谢谢
- I can take that, sir. - Thank you very much.
- 先生 我来拿吧 - 非常感谢
Joyce, can I borrow him for a second?
乔伊斯 我可以单独和他谈谈吗
Sure. I'll be in the car, okay?
当然 我在车里等你 好吗
Two minutes behind you.
两分钟后到
- Great. - You'll see her to the car, please, sir?
- 好的 - 请护送她到车里 可以吗
- Of course. - Thank you.
- 当然 - 谢谢
What's up?
什么事
So what's with the creepy guy with the cane?
那个拿手杖的怪人是干吗的
Someone I should know about?
要不要我去了解一下?
No, no, no. He's been at these meetings longer than I have.
不 他是这种会议的常客
He's fine.
没问题的
All right.
好吧
Listen, get back to the hotel, and get some rest, all right?
快回酒店吧 好好睡一觉
Yeah. Everything's fine.
好的 别担心
Great work tonight, Bobby.
今晚表现很棒 波比
- Thank you. - You're the man.
- 谢谢 - 看好你喔
Joyce?
乔伊斯?
What happened to him?
他怎么死的
They always tell you not to smoke at the gas station.
在加油站里抽烟
- This should wrap up the week for you. - Great.
- 这些够你忙一个礼拜了吧 - 是啊
What's up, man?
什么情况
I'm at a junkyard on 58th.
我在58号大街的废物堆积场
Why?
出什么事了
Call came in about a car crash.
有人报警这儿有起车祸
Car crash? Why are you there?
出车祸关你什么事
It's not just a car crash.
不仅仅是车祸那么简单
It's a trap.
又一个机关陷阱
How many bodies?
死了几个人
Enough pieces to make four.
拼起来后有四个
Okay, get everyone away from that crime scene till I get there.
我到那儿之前 所有人禁止进入犯罪现场
- Even Homicide, you got it? - Yeah.
- 重案组也不行 明白吗 - 明白
All right, I'm on the way.
好 我现在过去
Hello, Evan. I want to play a game.
你好 埃文 我想玩个游戏
The situation you find yourself in...
你所处的环境...
You, your girlfriend...
你 你的女友...
You have intimidated others
你因为别人的肤色
based on their physical differences.
而威胁他们
So, what do you think?
你怎么看
Why?
为什么
Why this display?
为什么设计成这样
Why them? Why now?
为什么选他们 为什么是这个时候
You know he likes to put on a show.
他就喜欢作秀给别人看
Well, there's gotta be something else.
肯定还有别的原因
Bag the other bodies.
把剩下的尸体打包
Get them back to the coroner's office right away.
送回警局后马上交给验尸官
We'll need them checked for anything resembling a clue.
看看是否能查出什么线索
Tattoos, piercings, skin cuttings.
比如纹身 耳洞 穿孔之类的
If that man has a cavity in his tooth, I want to know about it.
就算有蛀牙也要给我查出来
- Yes, sir. - All right.
- 是的 长官 - 好的
Gibson.
吉布森
Yeah?
怎么了
Hoffman was expecting you.
霍夫曼知道你要来
God damn.
该死的
(吉布森 亲眼看看吧)
Would you look at that?
你快看这个
Please get forensics in here.
叫鉴证科的人过来
Tell them to haul ass.
让他们迅速点
This needs to be dusted for prints.
查查上面的指纹
- All right. - Okay.
- 好的 - 去吧
Help!
救命
(生存)
Hello, Bobby.
你好 波比
I want to play a game.
我想玩个游戏
You have amassed wealth, fame, and notoriety,
你凭借着你的新书
based upon your story of survival.
让自己变得富有 声名远扬
Many have aided in your cause, but few know the truth.
许多人还因此资助你 却没人知道真相
You are a liar.
你根本就是个骗子
You and I both know you have never been in a trap,
你和我都清楚你从来没经历过机关陷阱
nor have you ever been tested.
你也从来没接受过考验
Today these lies will come full circle and you will learn
今天我就让谎言变成现实
if you truly have what it takes to call yourself a survivor.
你也将知道自己配不配被称为幸存者
The cage you find yourself in
现在关着你的这个笼子
will symbolize your rebirth.
将象征着你的重生
Joyce? No!
乔伊斯 不
Joyce! No!
Please, no.
求求你了 别这样
Within the next 60 minutes,
在接下来的60分钟里
you must stay upon the path of learning
你将经历重重考验
and traverse a series of obstacles
你必须穿越各种阻碍
to obtain access to your wife,
才能见到你的妻子
who you have also deceived.
那个还蒙在鼓里的妻子
If you fail to reach her before the clock runs out,
如果你在规定时间之内没能到她那儿
- she will die. - No.
- 她就死定了 - 不
Live or die, Bobby?
是生是死 波比
Make your choice.
由你选择
(重启你的人生)
Bobby!
波比
Help!
救命
Let me out!
放我出去
Bobby.
波比
Bobby! What's going on? What's going on?
波比 这到底是怎么回事 怎么回事
Another Jigsaw survivor has come forward.
又一名竖锯幸存者将为大家分享她的经历
As the city stays crippled in fear from the Jigsaw killings,
当整座城市都笼罩着拼图游戏的恐怖气氛
chilling new words from the latest survivor provide a reminder
最新的幸存者将用亲身经历讲述
of the physical and mental toll these deadly games can take.
拼图游戏给他们带来的心理和生理创伤
This horrible event was happening to me,
这件恐怖的事发生在我的身上
and in that moment,
那一刻
that moment that this thing
threatened to take everything away,
恐惧带走了一切
even the pain,
就连痛苦都带走了
I realized what I still had left to give.
我意识到我仍然要去付出
And I didn't want to let that go.
而且我不想让这种感觉消失
It gave me light.
它给了我光明
That pure moment of absolute horror gave me light.
在那个充满恐惧的时刻我感受到了光
And as wrong as this may seem,
也许听上去很荒谬
I'm better for enduring it.
但是我却越发地享受着它
I'm stronger.
我更加强大了
And, I must admit, I'm grateful for it.
我必须承认 我对此充满感激
I'm grateful it happened to me,
我很感激它发生在我身上
and I wish the same for everyone like me.
我希望每个幸存者都能有这种感觉
Joan is but one of a growing number of citizens...
琼是越来越多的受害者之一...
If something like that doesn't
如果连这种事
get you to change your perspective on life,
都不能改变你对生活的看法
I don't know what will.
也没什么能够改变了
Yeah.
的确
And if those people weren't so fucked up after their games,
如果他们在经历这种事情后不那么崩溃
they'd make a mint selling their stories.
也许他们可以尝试着出书了
(重启你的人生)
(自我反省)
That's a real clever design.
这玩意设计得挺精妙啊
Yours or your husband's?
是你还是你丈夫的杰作?
- Everything was him. - Right.
- 一切都是他造成的 - 你说得对
Well, here's my problem,
那我就有个问题了
that was left for me, and your fingerprints were all over it.
我搞不懂为什么这上面全是你的指纹
When you told me Hoffman had it in for you,
你告诉我霍夫曼追杀你的时候
you didn't mention that it was because you tried to kill him.
怎么不告诉我是因为你要干了他
There's a new game going on.
又一个拼图游戏开始了
Does that surprise you?
你不吃惊吗
- No. - No? No?
- 对 - 不吃惊吗
You're crazy, you know that?
你疯了 你知道吗
I knew you were crazy the minute I laid eyes on you.
我看你第一眼就知道你是个疯子
Crazy.
疯婆子
Okay, this is what we're gonna do, crazy.
好吧 我们这么干 疯婆子
Till I catch Mark Hoffman, this is your new home.
在我抓到马克·霍夫曼之前 你就住这儿
Get comfy.
好好休息
What makes you think he can't find me here?
你怎么知道他找不到这里呢
Jill, it's a safe house.
吉尔 这是安全屋
Safe house. Safe. House.
安全屋懂吗 安全的屋子
You get it?
听懂了吗
Gibson, this was sent here addressed to Jill.
吉布森 这个是寄给吉尔的
Hoffman knows our location.
霍夫曼知道我们在哪儿
God damn it. God damn it!
妈的 该死
What?
什么情况
We just had a small explosion here in a car
我们在犯罪现场有一台车
at the crime scene.
发生了小爆炸
Okay, is anyone hurt?
有人受伤吗
Holy shit!
我操
Rogers?
罗杰斯?
Rogers, you okay?
罗杰斯 你还好吗
Yeah.
很好
Get out of there. You get the bomb squad to sweep the yard.
离开现场 叫防爆小组清理现场
Don't touch anything else until it's clean.
清理之前什么都不要碰
- Got it. - All right.
- 收到 - 挂了
Play it.
放吧
Hello, Gibson.
你好 吉布森
Been a long time.
好久不见了
What I want is simple,
我的要求很简单
give me Jill Tuck.
把吉尔·塔克交给我
You're protecting her despite the fact
你居然不顾前嫌保护她
that she had direct knowledge throughout,
她利用她熟练的拼图游戏知识
which makes her complicit in every death.
参与了每一宗案件
I'll make you a deal.
我和你做笔交易
Give her to me,
把她交给我
the game stops, and no one else dies.
游戏结束 也不会再死人了
If not, everyone dies and you'll be to blame.
如果不同意 你们的死就将归咎于你
Make your choice.
由你决定
The clock is ticking.
时间不等人
Let's get her down to the holding cell at the station.
把她押到局里的拘留所去
Lock it down. No one gets in without my authority.
把她锁起来 没有我的同意谁都不能进
Got it.
明白
(重新排序)
Oh, my God.
天啊
Oh, God!
No! Please!
不要啊 拜托了
No! Please, help! Please!
不 求求你 救命啊 求你了
Please, no!
求你 不要啊
God damn it!
妈的
Bobby. Bobby, help me!
波比 波比 快救救我
You've got to get me out of here.
你得把我救出去
I can't move, Bobby.
我动不了 波比
Please, help me!
求你了 救救我
Okay, okay, okay. Just relax.
好的 好的 放松
Help me! Do something!
救救我 想想办法
Don't leave me.
别离开我
Hello, Bobby.
你好 波比
Before you is one of your trusted colleagues.
你面前的是你最信任的同事
She has been your publicist for years, knowing your lies
她深知你的谎言却帮你宣传这么多年
but choosing to speak no evil.
她一直替你隐瞒
She has been richly rewarded for her words,
她曾因为口才而获得丰厚的报酬
but today she will be rewarded for her silence.
但今天她要是不闭嘴就会受到惩罚
In the X- ray, you will see a key,
这张X光片里 你会看到一把钥匙
the key to Nina's survival, which will shut off her device.
解救尼娜的钥匙 它能关闭这个机关
But there's a tach.
但是有时间限制
You have one minute to pull the fish hook from her stomach,
你只有一分钟把鱼钩从她的胃里拉出来
and unlock her device
并解除机关
or else the four spikes will penetrate her throat,
时间一过那4根钉子就会穿过她的喉咙
- silencing Nina forever. - Fuck!
- 让尼娜永远闭嘴 - 操
Remember, the spikes will also advance
记住 每次室内的声音分贝太高
each time the decibel level in this room
钉子都会向前伸一段
rises above a whisper, killing her even sooner.
那样她就死得更快了
Will Nina live or die, Bobby? The choice is yours.
尼娜是死是活 波比 由你选择
- Help me. Help! - No! No!
- 救命 救命啊 - 不 不
Just shut up.
闭嘴好吗
Stay with me, okay?
别出声好吗
Do it.
来吧
No. No. No.
不 不 不
Okay, stay with me. Stay with me.
别出声 保持安静
It's gonna be okay. Look at me.
一会儿就好了 看着我
Look at me.
看着我
No! Nina, quiet. Nina.
不 尼娜 闭嘴 尼娜
Please. Please, for me.
拜托了 求你了 就当为我
Just shut the fuck up.
你他妈给我闭嘴
I'm gonna get this out.
我帮你拿出来
No! No!
不 不
Just do it, Bobby. Just fucking do it.
继续 波比 你他妈继续啊
Bobby!
波比
No!
不
Why wouldn't you just shut the fuck up?
你他妈闭上嘴会死吗
You just needed to shut up!
你不叫不就没事了吗
No! Oh, my God!
不 天啊
No! Help!
不 救命啊
Help! Help!
救命 救命啊
(幸存 波比·达恩 著)
Here you are, ma'am. Take care.
好了 女士 保重
Ma'am, your name?
女士 你的名字叫什么
Sara, without an "H."
纱拉 有"纟"的那个纱
I just want to say I love your book so much.
我就想说我太喜欢你的书了
I just felt like I could feel everything that you went through.
我可以真切地感受到你的那次经历
I feel like it changed my life.
它改变了我的生活
I appreciate that, ma'am.
谢谢你 女士
I really do. Thank you.
真的很感谢 谢谢
Thank you.
我该谢谢你才是
Your name, sir?
你叫什么名字 先生
John.
约翰
With an "H," Without an "H," It doesn't matter.
写不写"纟"都无所谓
We'll go with John with an "H" this time.
那我这次就写带"纟"的约翰吧
You got quite an army working for you here, don't you?
你有一个干练的团队吧 不是吗
Must be spreading a pretty good word.
他们一定到处替你宣传吧
Well, we try to reach as many people as possible, you know?
我们总是尽可能多的去帮助别人
You don't see anything wrong with that?
你没发现有什么问题吗
No. No, sir, I don't.
没有啊 先生 我不觉得有什么问题
You know, history is a passion for me.
听着 我热爱历史
And in ancient Egypt if you were speaking under oath,
在古埃及 如果你立下誓言的话
you were required to say,
你必须要宣誓
"If I'm lying, take me to the quarries."
"如果我说谎的话 就把我带去采石场"
That mean anything to you?
知道什么意思吗
No, sir. No, sir, it doesn't.
不 先生 不知道
Well, I'll tell you what it means.
那我来告诉你
It means if you knowingly lied on the public record
意思是如果你对公众说谎的话
that you were subject to a period of enslavement.
你将接受被奴役的惩罚
What are you implying here, sir?
先生 你想暗示我什么
I'm not implying anything.
我什么都没暗示你
Move along, buddy. He signed your book.
往前走吧 伙计 他已经给你签名了
Thanks for the signature.
谢谢你的签名
Nice picture, but I don't need it.
照片不错 不过我用不着
We've met.
我们见过面的
Adam, Gibson says he wants you on these right away.
亚当 吉布森说他想让你检查这些尸体
They're from the junkyard.
废物堆积场那边运回来的
Make your choice.
由你决定
The clock is ticking.
时间不等人
See that?
看到了吗
Yeah.
看到了
I know that from somewhere.
我知道那是哪儿
Hey, I've got something over here.
我这儿有发现
We might know who's in the game.
我们也许能找到受害者
This was just sent to us.
有人传了这个过来
It was taken from a security camera downtown.
市区里的一个摄像头拍下来的
The guy's name is Bobby Dagen.
这个人叫波比·达恩
- Familiar? - No.
- 熟悉吗 - 不熟悉
He's a Jigsaw survivor
他是个拼图游戏的幸存者
who's milking it on talk shows.
并通过参加谈话节目赚钱
His wife and handlers are also missing.
他的老婆和他们的团队都失踪了
(通过承担义务实现自我价值)
Joyce?
乔伊斯?
Who is it? Who's there?
谁 谁在那儿
- Suzanne. - Who is that?
- 苏珊娜 - 你是谁
For fuck's sake, Bobby. Bobby.
太好了 波比 波比
Bobby, get me out of here.
波比 救我出去
Bobby, help me.
波比 救救我
- Is Cale here? - Who the fuck knows?
- 凯尔在这儿吗 - 谁他妈知道
Get this off of me, Bobby! Get this off of me!
把它给我解开 波比 快解开
Hello, Bobby.
你好 波比
That feeling running through your body is fear,
现在恐惧已经贯穿你的身体
the fear of not knowing if you have what it takes to survive.
这是因为你不知道你是否有资格生存
Before you is your lawyer
你面前的 是你的律师
who swore an oath of ethics,
她无视曾经宣誓的道德规范
but chose to see no evil in order to benefit herself.
选择蒙上自己的双眼 为自己牟利
Once her device begins to rotate,
她的机关一旦开始转动
it will pierce her eyes and mouth
她的眼睛和嘴将被刺穿
if you don't delay its movement for at least 30 seconds.
你要让这个机关停止转动至少30秒钟
To do this, you must step into the other
为此 你必须站到另外一个机器上
machine and lift the bars to the highest position
把那两个横杠举到最高的位置
long enough to close the circuit, slowing down her device.
直到关闭机关 放慢她机关的转动速度
If you do nothing, she will wind to her death
如果不这么做的话 在时间到之前
before the clock runs out.
她就会被刺死了
Do you have what it takes to help her?
你是否愿意挺身而出去救她呢
Make your choice.
由你决定
Bobby, please!
波比 求你了
Bobby, please get me out!
波比 求你把我救出去吧
Get me the fuck...
快他妈的救我
Oh, God!
天啊
No, no! Bobby, please!
不 不 波比 求你了
Please, help me!
求你了 救救我
Oh, God! Oh, God!
天啊 天啊
Please, hurry! Hurry!
求你了 快点 快点
Come on, Bobby, please! Hurry!
快点 波比 求你了 再快点
Come on! Bobby, come on!
快点啊 波比 快点啊
Hurry! Please! Please, hurry!
快 拜托了 求求你了 快啊
Bobby, please, hurry!
波比 求你了 快点
Hurry!
快点啊
- Yes! - Yes, Bobby! Yes!
- 成功了 - 好样的 波比
Come on!
不是吧
Bobby, no.
波比 不
No! God, no!
不 天啊 不
No! Bobby!
不 波比
Please, no! Bobby, no!
求你了 不 波比 不
Come on, Bobby. Please! Get me out of here!
快点 波比 求你了 快救我出去
Come on!
快停啊
Bobby, please!
波比 求你了
No!
不
Oh, God.
天啊
Oh, my God. Bobby, stay there.
我的天啊 波比 坚持住
Bobby, please, no!
波比 求你了 不
No! No!
不 不
No!
不
Please, please!
求你了 求求你了
No!
不
Oh, God!
天啊
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
No. No.
不 不
Help!
救命啊
Do you know this guy?
你认识他吗
I've seen him on TV, but I don't know him.
电视上见过 但不认识
Did your husband?
你老公认识吗
I don't know.
不知道
You sure you don't know him?
你确定不认识他吗
Yeah, I'm sure.
是的 确定
All right then.
那好吧
Lock it up.
锁上
Hoffman just sent an E- mail with an MPEG attachment.
霍夫曼刚才用邮件发来一个视频
I'm just searching the IP address.
我正在追踪他的IP地址
Can you find out where it came from?
能查到是哪儿发过来的吗
It depends on how many proxy servers he filtered it through,
这得看他的邮件经过了几个代理服务器
but it was time- delayed, so it'll leave fingerprints.
但这个是定时邮件 应该查得出的
Play it.
放吧
Hello, Gibson.
你好 吉布森
Once again, we're at a moral crossroad.
我们又到了道德的十字路口
I don't blame you for not giving me Jill Tuck,
你不把吉尔·塔克交给我 我不怪你
but you shouldn't let an old grudge cloud your judgment.
但你不能用过去的恩怨影响你的判断
Look to where you're being led.
看看你现在的处境
Look beyond the crossroad to the clear dawn.
过了十字路口 便有晴朗黎明
Do you see it?
你看到了吗
I get it. Let's go.
我知道了 我们走
(忽视诋毁者)
Joyce?
乔伊斯?
Cale?
凯尔?
Bobby? Bobby?
波比 波比
Listen to me. Cale. Cale, I can see you, okay?
听我说 凯尔 我能看到你
Cale, don't move.
凯尔 别动
Bobby, where the hell are you?
波比 你他妈在哪儿
You got to help me, Bobby.
你要救救我 波比
Do you know where Joyce is?
你知道乔伊斯在哪儿吗
What the fuck? I can't see, man.
搞什么鬼 我看不见了
How the fuck would I know where Joyce is?
我他妈怎么会知道乔伊斯在哪儿
I'm about to lose my shit!
我要抓狂了
Do I know where Joyce is?
我怎么知道乔伊斯在哪儿
I'm fucking blind, man.
我他妈都瞎了
Okay, Cale. Cale, do not move.
好 凯尔 别乱动
I got this thing around my fucking neck.
那个鬼东西缠在我脖子上
I can't fucking breathe.
我他妈不能呼吸了
Don't fucking move. We're not on the ground floor.
别乱动 我们离地面很高
A lot of this floor is missing.
这层地板没搭全 好多地方是空的
Just don't move, okay?
所以千万别动 听见没
Fuck. You gotta help me.
我操 你一定得救我啊
Get me fucking down, Bobby! Fuck! Fuck me!
救我啊 波比 我操
Cale, there's a tape.
凯尔 这儿有盘磁带
- What fucking tape? - There's a tape.
- 什么磁带 - 这儿有盘带子
Shut up. I'm gonna play the tape.
安静 我来播录音
Hello, Bobby. Across from you is your closest friend.
你好 波比 对面是你最铁的哥们儿
He knows all your sins,
他对你的罪行了如指掌
yet he acts as though he hears no evil.
却装作一无所知
Today, what he hears
今天 他将了解
will be the difference between life and death.
生与死的差别
Bobby, you must help Cale walk over the planks,
波比 你必须引导凯尔走过独木桥
and get as close to you as possible.
让他尽量靠近你
Find your own way across the beams to the key.
你必须想办法穿过横梁拿到钥匙
You must get it to him over the last span between you.
在最后时限内把钥匙给他
If the noose around Cale's neck is not removed within 60 seconds,
如果60秒后凯尔脖子上的绳套还没摘掉
a winch will be engaged, and your secret will be left hanging.
他就等着绞车伺候 你的秘密也将永远成为秘密
Does Cale live or die, Bobby? The choice is yours.
凯尔是死是活 就看你怎么选了 波比
Bobby!
波比
Oh, God.
天哪
Cale. Cale, listen to me.
凯尔 凯尔 听我说
Listen to me.
听我说
Shut the fuck up and you listen to me for once.
把嘴闭上 听我说
Listen, I'm gonna walk you through this, okay, buddy?
听着 哥们儿 我这就来救你 好吗
I'm blind. You fucking come to me.
我什么都看不见 你他妈赶快过来啊
I'm gonna try to get as close to you as I can, buddy.
兄弟 我现在就来
I'm fucking listening to you. Talk me fucking through this.
我他妈听你的 快教我怎么走
I want you to shuffle to your right.
你慢慢往右边挪
Just shuffle exactly to your right.
找准你的正右方移动
You're gonna feel a plank at your foot. Yes, yes.
感觉到有块木板 对 对
Yes, yes, perfect. I need you to head out on that plank.
对 非常好 我要你向木头的方向移动
- Oh, fuck. - Yes.
- 我操 - 就是这样
Okay, I got it. I got it. I got it!
好的 踩到了 我踩到了
Fuck this.
我操
Okay, Cale, I'm on the way.
好 凯尔 我正过来呢
Fuck. Fuck. Okay, all right.
操 操 好的 好的
Now there's gonna be a plank in front of you.
往前走会有块木板
- Okay. - You're gonna have to go
- 好的 - 你还得
about 10 degrees to your right.
在你1点钟的方向
I got it. I got it.
踩到了 踩到了
- Come on, keep fucking talking to me. - Okay. Okay, Cale.
- 快点 你他妈继续说呀 - 好 好 凯尔
- Feel where the plank... - I got it.
- 找找木头在哪儿 - 找到了
Okay.
好
Oh, God! What the fuck was that, man?
天哪 这他妈是什么啊
It's okay, Cale. It was a bottle. It was a bottle.
别管它 凯尔 就是个瓶子 瓶子而已
- What the fuck was that? - It's okay. It was a bottle.
- 什么啊 - 没事的 就是个瓶子
- You're gonna be fine. - Okay.
- 你会没事的 - 好的
Fuck. Okay.
操 好吧
You got it, buddy.
就是这样 兄弟
You got it. Now you're gonna feel a second plank.
就是这样 你现在会碰到第二块木板
- You'll feel it with your foot. - I got it.
- 用脚找找看 - 有了
Feel it with your foot.
用脚找找
Get me out of this fucking thing, Bobby.
救救我啊 哥们
Step up onto the plank.
踩到木板上
Oh, fuck. Oh, God.
我操 天哪
Relax. You're okay.
别紧张 没事的
No! No!
不 不
Cale, hang on. Cale.
凯尔 挺住啊 凯尔
Fuck. Fuck.
我操 我操
Bobby. Bobby.
波比 波比
I got the key but... Cale!
我拿到钥匙了但是...凯尔
I'm gonna throw you the key.
我这就把钥匙丢给你
Cup your hands closer to your chest!
双手摊开摆在一块儿 在胸前捧好
I'm gonna throw it on three, all right?
我数三下 就丢过去 你接好了
One,
一
Two,
二
Three.
三
No.
不
Oh, fuck me.
我操
No! God damn it, no!
不 我操 不
Cale!
凯尔
No. Cale.
不 凯尔
There's nothing here.
什么都没有
Yes, there is.
谁说没有
Right there.
就在这儿
Why would he want us to come here?
他为什么引我们来这儿
For me to remember.
让我记住他的大恩大德
This is where he saved my life.
他在这儿救过我
When I was in uniform I responded to a distress call here.
我当巡警那会儿 有一次到这儿来执行任务
Back when this place was
那时候这里是
a flophouse for junkies and homeless people.
毒贩和流浪汉的天堂
Freeze! Don't you fucking move.
不许动 你他妈再动试试
Drop the gun.
把枪放下
He didn't know what hit him.
他死得挺冤的
Yeah, he assaulted me,
没错 他是袭击了我
but it shouldn't have been a death sentence.
但罪不至死啊
Next time, you shoot first.
下次 要先发制人
I had no choice but to report Hoffman for brutality.
没办法 我只能举报霍夫曼暴力执法
You owe me.
你欠我的
What happened?
然后呢
He got a promotion is what happened. And I got put on an island.
然后他升官了啊 我就被调走了
A year later, I transferred to IA, busted three of his guys.
一年后 我调到内务部　成功起诉了他三个弟兄
He swore he'd get me back, and here we are.
他扬言报复 所以把我们弄这儿来了
This place was called Crossroads Manufacturing before it closed.
这厂子关门前叫十字路制造公司
"Look beyond the crossroads."
"过了十字路口"
"To the clear dawn."
"便有晴朗黎明"
I don't follow you.
什么意思
The man he killed was
他打死的那个男的
released from Clear Dawn Psychiatric Hospital
曾经在晴朗黎明精神病院住院
when the state shut it down.
医院被政府查封后他就出来了
That building's been abandoned for years.
那楼废弃很多年了
That's where the game is being played.
游戏就在那儿进行
All right, you get back, you stay with Jill Tuck.
好的 你回去 和吉尔·塔克待在一起
Don't let her out of your sight.
别让她离开你的视线
(珍惜所爱)
- Joyce? - Bobby. Bobby!
- 乔伊斯? - 波比 波比
Bobby, I'm here.
波比 我在这儿
- Joyce. - Bobby, can you hear me?
- 乔伊斯 - 波比 听得见吗
Joyce, I can hear you. I can see you.
乔伊斯 我听得见你说话 我看见你了
Bobby, I can see you, too.
波比 我也看见你了
Yes, baby.
亲爱的 看见了吗
- Get me out of here. - Baby, I'm on my way.
- 救我出去 - 亲爱的 我就来
Who's doing this? Why?
谁要害我们啊 为什么
- Why is this happening? - Please, baby, I'm on the way.
- 为什么会这样 - 再坚持一会儿 我马上就来
- Just hang on, okay? - Hurry. Please hurry.
- 坚持住好吗 - 求求你 快点儿来
There's got to be a tape.
应该有带子的
Hello, Bobby.
你好 波比
Before you is the door that leads to your wife.
面前这扇门能带你到你妻子那儿
However, you must first make a choice.
但是 你得先做个选择
As you may have guessed,
你可能已经猜到
your decision will be as difficult as pulling teeth.
这个选择有如拔牙般艰难
The lock before you requires a four- digit combination to open.
你面前的锁需要四位数字组合才能解开
However, if it is access you seek
但要想开门
then a true sacrifice will have to be made.
必须做出真正的牺牲
Watch and learn, Bobby.
看好了 波比
The necessary numbers have been etched onto two of your teeth.
密码就刻在你的两颗牙上
Look to the chart as a reference for which teeth to pull
墙上的图会教你怎么拔牙
and in which order to enter the digits.
密码的顺序是什么
Time is ticking down.
事不宜迟
You must make your decision quickly.
赶快决定
Bobby!
波比
I don't want you to see this, baby, okay?
我不想让你看这个 亲爱的
Oh, my God.
我的天哪
No.
不
No!
Left side clear.
左翼安全
Clear.
安全
- Clear. - Clear.
- 安全 - 安全
Change your position.
调整位置
The game's still on.
游戏还在继续
- Let's go. - Move to the second level.
- 上 - 到二层去
- Clear. - Clear.
- 安全 - 安全
Clear.
安全
Go.
上
- Clear up. - All clear.
- 没人 - 一个人都没有
Move, move.
快 快
- Moving in. - Moving in.
- 进去 - 进去
- Clear. - We're clear.
- 安全 - 我们这儿也没人
Block it off.
封锁起来
- What? - I found where that MPEG came from.
- 说话 - 我找到视频的IP地址了
- Where? - A business called Pete's Auto Body
- 哪里 - 皮特汽修公司
on 58th Street.
在58号街
- The junkyard. - The location of the car trap?
- 废物堆积场 - 之前那个车库游戏吗
Yeah, that's correct.
对 没错
Okay, you guys keep moving.
你们继续在这里搜查
Where are you going?
你去哪儿
To get Hoffman.
抓霍夫曼
Okay, let's move it.
好 大家行动
Rogers.
我是罗杰斯
Yeah.
好
What? What happened?
怎么啦 发生什么事啦
Gibson's got Hoffman's location.
吉布森知道霍夫曼在哪儿了
The game isn't over.
游戏还没结束
Another body.
又一具尸体了
Hold.
等等
We got a live one.
还有活口
Can't cross here. Let's go.
这边过不去 撤
Hey. Go get your shotguns. You come follow me.
走 拿好枪 跟在我后面
Give me your gun.
枪给我
Hoffman, freeze.
霍夫曼 不许动
I want you to slowly put your hands in the air.
慢慢把手举起来
Joyce.
乔伊斯
Bobby.
波比
Bobby, I knew you'd make it.
波比 我就知道你会来
I knew you'd find me.
我知道你会找到我的
I am so sorry.
抱歉
I knew you could do it.
我知道你可以的
I knew you'd come.
我知道你会来的
Get me out.
救救我
Bobby. Oh, my God.
波比 我的天哪
There's gotta be another way.
一定有别的方法
Hello, Bobby. You have almost completed your rebirth.
波比 你好 你即将获得重生
However, your final task will be your most difficult.
但最后的任务也最为艰难
The woman before you symbolizes your success.
面前的女人象征着你的成功
She is your trophy.
她是你的战利品
And she has seen the good in your message,
她只看到你的好
despite its dishonest beginnings.
却看不到你虚伪的真面目
What's he talking about?
他在说什么
Today, we will see if you can truly earn her love.
现在 我们就看看你是否真值得她爱
To prove your status as a survivor,
要证明你是个名副其实的幸存者
you must overcome a game that should be all too familiar.
你必须通过一个再熟悉不过的游戏
- No. - You supposedly survived it once already,
- 不 - 既然上次已经通关
so it should be easy to survive once again.
这回应该是轻车熟路了
Pierce the hooks through your chest muscles,
把这些钩子扎进你的胸肌后
and the game will begin.
游戏开始
In order to free yourself and your wife,
要想解救你和你妻子
you must hoist yourself with these chains,
你必须借助这些链条把自己举起来
and connect the extension
在有限的时间内
cords above you before the clock expires.
把上面的延长电路连接起来
Both hands will be needed to complete this task.
该任务需要双手并用
But that should be simple.
但应该很简单
For, as you claim to understand,
你说你明白
the pectoral muscles can easily support your weight.
胸肌承受你的体重根本不在话下
So I ask you, Bobby,
所以我问你 波比
when you embrace every day as if it is your last,
你会把每天都当做生命的最后一天来珍惜吗
will it be with your wife?
今天会是你们夫妻的最后一天吗
Make your choice.
自己选吧
What's he talking about?
他在说什么
Baby, I'm so sorry.
亲爱的 对不起
I lied.
我骗了你
I was never in a trap.
我从没玩过什么游戏
Clear.
安全
How could you let me believe that?
你干吗要这么骗我
I'm gonna make this right.
我会将功赎罪的
You don't deserve to be there.
你不该受这种折磨
I'm your wife.
我是你妻子
How could you lie to me?
你怎么连我都骗
I know that from somewhere.
貌似在哪儿听过
Make your choice. Clock's ticking.
自己选择吧 计时开始
Bag the other bodies.
把尸体装起来
Get them back to the coroner's office right away.
马上送去尸检
What is this, sir?
长官 这是什么
Hoffman tapped into the station's security system.
霍夫曼打入了警察局的安全系统
He's been watching us the whole time.
他一直在监视我们
Oh, my God.
我的天哪
- This is Palmer. - Listen.
- 您好 我是帕默 - 听着
You get every available officer back to the station.
马上召集所有警力回警署
I'm sorry, sir?
抱歉 长官
Right now.
马上
Sir.
长官
Gibson, are you still there? Gibson.
吉布森 你还在吗 吉布森
(警告过你)
- Door's locked! - We're locked in!
- 门锁着 - 我们被锁在里面了
Gas! Gas!
有毒气
Look for an exit.
快找出口
I love you, Joyce.
我爱你 乔伊斯
I never lied about that.
这我从来没有说谎
I love you. I love you.
我爱你 我爱你
Bobby, I love you.
波比 我爱你
No! Oh, my God.
不 我的天哪
No.
不
Gibson.
吉布森
You can do it. You can do it.
你一定行的 一定行
Oh, my God.
我的天哪
Bobby, I love you.
波比 我爱你
You can do it.
你没问题的
Hang on. Hang on. Hang on.
坚持 坚持 坚持住
Pull. Pull, Bobby. I know you can do it.
拉 拉 波比 我知道你能行的
Pull.
拉
Oh, my God. Keep going.
我的天哪 加油
Bobby, you can do it. Oh, my God.
波比 我知道你没问题的 我的天哪
Bobby!
波比
Pull!
拉啊
What was that?
那边怎么回事
That's it, pull. Pull!
就是这样 拉 往下拉
Pull.
拉
Hurry!
快点
Pull. You're almost there.
拉 就快到了
Fight, Bobby. You can do it.
加油 波比 你肯定行的
Someone's out there.
外面有人
Oh, my God. No!
我的天哪 不
Help me! Help me!
救命 救命
Help me! No!
救命啊 不
I've been looking for you.
我找你很久了
How do I look?
我看起来怎么样
Bitch.
臭婊子
Help me!
救命
Bobby, please, reach.
波比 求你了 伸手
Go.
加油
Bobby, reach.
波比 伸手
Hurry.
加油
Reach. Reach!
抓住 抓住它
You can do it, Bobby.
你可以的 波比
Bobby, reach. Reach.
波比 伸手啊
One more. Reach. You can do it. Bobby!
再来一次 伸手 你可以的 波比
Bobby, you can do it.
波比 你没问题的
Bobby!
波比
No!
不
Bobby!
波比
No. Bobby!
不 波比
Joyce!
乔伊斯
Bobby!
波比
Joyce!
乔伊斯
Bobby! Bobby!
波比 波比
Joyce! Joyce!
乔伊斯 乔伊斯
Bobby!
波比
You fucking cunt.
臭婊子
No! Bobby!
不 波比
Joyce!
乔伊斯
No!
不
Bobby!
波比
Joyce!
乔伊斯
Game over.
游戏结束
Over the last two hours,
过去的两个小时内
it seems our entire city has been shaken to its core.
本市警视厅发生了特大恶性杀人事件
In addition to the nine police employees killed tonight,
今晚共有九名警员丧生
Jill Tuck, the wife of
此外 连环杀手约翰·克莱默的遗孀
serial killer John Kramer, has been found dead.
吉尔·塔克也被暴徒杀害
Citizens are being advised to report any activity,
在此非常时期 市民一旦发现任何可疑行为
even remotely suspicious, at this time,
请立即报警
as blockades are being set up at major intersections
警方正全面封锁
within a 30- mile radius,
案发现场方圆30英里内的主要道路
surrounding what will be considered the largest attack
本案被认为是
on this city's police department in our history.
本市有史以来最大的袭警事件
Any citizens with information leading to the apprehension...
市民若发现相关线索的...
What the fuck?
我操
Hello, Dr. Gordon.
你好啊 戈登医生
You are perhaps my greatest asset.
你也许是我最宝贵的遗产
Congratulations, Dr. Gordon. You survived.
恭喜你 戈登医生 你活下来了
Without you, my work over the
多亏了你 我的竖锯事业
last few years would not have been possible.
在过去几年才突飞猛进
Jeff's wife.
杰夫的妻子
Dr. Lynn Denlon.
琳·迪伦医生
She'll be perfect.
她是最理想的人选
My eyes! I can't see!
我的眼睛 我看不见了
(我知道你是谁)
That having been said, I have a request.
话虽如此 我仍然有个请求
Watch over Jill.
替我照顾好吉尔
And should anything happen to her,
万一她出了什么事
I want you to act immediately on my behalf.
我要你立即采取行动
In return for that, I will keep no more secrets from you.
作为回报 我会对你坦白一切
I've shown you a lot of places.
我已经带你见识了好几个游戏场所
But there is one that will be,
但有个地方
perhaps, the most meaningful to you.
可能对你才最有意义
I don't think so.
你想得倒美
What do you think you're doing?
你到底要干什么
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
你他妈想要干什么
No!
不
You can't fucking do this to me.
你他妈不能这么对我
Fuck you. No!
我操 不
Game over.
游戏结束
No!
不